Guide to the Manny Harriman Video Oral History Collection ALBA.VIDEO.048
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series I: Manny Harriman Oral History Project
  - Toutoloff, John Interview, Dec 6, 1986 (Box 16, Item ALBA V 48-192)
    Second of two tapes containing interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran John Toutoloff.
  - Troxil, Stephen (Steve) discussed by Molly Troxil, Jul 24, 1985 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-193)
    Interview with Molly Troxil, wife of Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Steve Troxil.
  - Van der Schelling, Bart discussed by Edna Van der Schelling, Mar 17, 1986 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-194)
    Interview with Edna Van der Schelling, wife of Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Bart Van der Schelling.
  - Veltford Jr., Theodore (Ted) Interview, Jun 24, 1985 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-195)
    Interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Ted Veltford, Jr.
  - Veterans (Group): MacLeod, Donald (Don) Interview; Edward Bender Interview; Stanley (Stan) Junas Interview; Sidney (Sid) Levine Interview; Eugene Poling Interview, undated (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-196)
    Tape contains five interviews[?]. Interviews with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veterans Don MacLeod, Ed Bender, Stan Junas, Sid Levine, and Eugene Poling.
  - Wallach, Harry Interview, Nov 3, 1986 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-197)
    First of two tapes containing interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Harry Wallach.
  - Wallach, Harry Interview, Nov 3, 1986 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-198)
    Second of two tapes containing interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Harry Wallach.
  - Warren, Alvin R. Interview, Sep 25, 1986 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-199)
    First of two tapes containing interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Alvin P. Warren.
  - Warren, Alvin R. Interview, Sep 25, 1986 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-200)
    Second of two tapes containing interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Alvin P. Warren.
  - Watt, George Interview, Sep 11, 1986 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-201)
    First of two tapes containing interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran George Watt.
  - Watt, George Interview, Sep 11, 1986 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-202)
    Second of two tapes containing interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran George Watt.
  - Weiner, Milton Interview, Aug 22, 1985 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-203)
    Interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Milton Weiner.
  - Whalen, Joseph Interview, Aug 22, 1985 (Box 17, Item ALBA V 48-204)
    Interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Joseph Whalen.
  - Wheeler, William (Bill) Interview, Mar 14, 1986 (Box 18, Item ALBA V 48-205)
    Interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Bill Wheeler.
  - Wildegans, Gustave Interview, Aug 16, 1986 (Box 18, Item ALBA V 48-206)
    First of two tapes containing interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Gustave Wildegans.
  - Wildegans, Gustave Interview, Aug 16, 1986 (Box 18, Item ALBA V 48-207)
    Second of two tapes containing interview with Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran Gustave Wildegans.
  - Shantzek, Michael Interview (Unfinished up until the Ebro Offensive), Feb 1987 (Box 18, Item ALBA V 48-208)
  - Temple, Lenora Interview, May 22, 1987 (Box 18, Item ALBA V 48-209)
    Nurse
  - DVD Viewing Copies of Interviews (Box 19)
  - Digitbeta Preservation Copies of Interviews (Box 20)
- Series II: General Subjects, Events, Memorials, etc.
  - Subseries IIA: Video (Box 21)
    - Alhambra (I-366), Gerona (560-1568), Banyuelos-Bisalu (1568-1682), VAND (1747-1931), Undated (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-210)
    - American Jewish Choral Society - 36th Concert, June 3, 1990 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-211)
    - Democratic Convention '88, Day Four, 1988 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-212)
    - El Monte People, 1983 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-213)
    - Estell and Church (Nicaragua), 1983 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-214)
    - Fairfay and Poker Game, Jan. 1984 & 1985 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-215)
    - Father Molino in Nicaragua, 1985 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-216)
    - Goffman, Irving Memorial (Excerpts For): Manny, Parade - Irving Goffman (1 Hr.), Undated (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-217)
    - Goffman, Irving Memorial (Excerpts For): Manny Parade Irving Goffman (1 Hr.), Undated (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-218)
    - Goffman, Irving Memorial - Unitarian Church, Aug 5, 1989 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-219)
    - Goffman, Irving Memorial - Unitarian Church, Aug 5, 1989 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-220)
    - Goffman, Irving Composite: Manny Parade (National Board Copy), Undated (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-221)
    - Harriman, Emanuel (Sam Nahman), Undated (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-222)
    - Lincoln Brigade Ambulances to Nicaragua (Copy of NBC Program), 1986 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-223)
    - May Day 1945 VALB & Others (Taken by Manny Harriman) (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-224)
    - May Day 1946 (Second Generation VALB) (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-225)
    - May Day 1946 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-226)
    - May Day 1946 (From Film of That Time) (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-227)
    - Managua Parade, 1983 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-228)
    - Matagalpas, Nicaragua, 1983 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-229)
    - Mexico (Chichinitza), Jan. 1984 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-230)
    - Mt. St. Helena Oregon, Aug 27, 1985 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-231)
    - Northwest Demo: Ambulances for Nicaragua in San Francisco (D-888 Tape 1), 1985 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-232)
    - NY Vets Dinner, Apr 26, 1985 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-233)
    - P.O.W. Brentwood, 1987 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-234)
    - San Francisco Demo: Ambulances for Nicaragua (Tape 2), July 27, 1985 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-235)
    - Street Fair, N.Y., 1985 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-236)
    - Trip to Mount Shasta, 1985 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-237)
    - VALB Dinner - Hayward, California, Feb 1985 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-238)
    - Second Vets Dinner: Madrid, Oct 28, 1988 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-239)
    - Vets Administrations (AMX POW), Jan 7, 1986 (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-240)
    - Unidentified Video, Undated (Box 21, Item ALBA V 48-241)
  - Subseries IIB: Audio (Box 22)
    - Goffman, Irving, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-243)
    - Goffman, Irving (3B is Blank), Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-244)
    - Goldstein, Butch: ALBA Film Project "The Good Fight" #1 & #2, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-245)
    - Goldstein, Butch: ALBA Film Project "The Good Fight" #3, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-246)
    - Goldstein, Butch (45/1/1 ?), Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-247)
    - Goldstein, Butch #3: V.O. Int., ALBA Film Project, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-248)
    - Harriman, Manny: Death Speech & Poetry and Life, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-249)
    - Harriman, Manny: [My Illustrious Forgotten ?] pt. I, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-250)
    - Harriman, Manny: [My Illustrious Forgotten?] pt. II, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-251)
    - Harriman Trip: Conversation on a bus going to [Bilchete Gandesa?] Spain - Son & Father returning / Geisen, Carl - P.O.W. [expedition?], 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-252)
    - Harriman Trip: [Courthouse Jamason 0 Steven on T1 / ? ? Col Roy Tangere ?], 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-253)
    - Harriman Trip: Discussion after historian lunch (both sides), October 19, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-254)
    - Harriman Trip: Gerona 1983 - Pia Tarres (0-195), Huerta (195-394) (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-255)
    - Harriman Trip: Huerta (A trip to the Past / Trip to the Past Songs Christian Evangelist, Spain 1983), Oct 11, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-256)
    - Harriman Trip: Huerta - A walk into the past [Iberia ? Rome ? and Jewish ?], 55 on our Huerta / Huerta a walk into the past Jewish Barrio in Spain, Oct 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-257)
    - Harriman Trip: Dr. La Porta in Isaac Nahmans House (Spanish Town Jewish Barrio: site Tarras) / Unknown Speaker on Gerona History, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-258)
    - Harriman Trip: Madrid 1983 - Cemetary Visit - [Longing Wreath ?] / [Passamonia?] on beginning of tape Villa Nuova (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-259)
    - Harriman Trip: Marcos, Luis - Writer of the Jews and Us. Letter from [Hammanides?] to family / Mayor of Gerona - [Rosemary of the Store?]. Louis Marcos, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V48-260)
    - Harriman Trip: Marcos, Luis & Grand, Samuel - Lunch in Gerona Spain (A Historical Conference), 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-261)
    - Harriman Trip: Margoles, Jamie (Historian) / Spanish Evangelist Songs, Oct 17, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-262)
    - Harriman Trip: Partido Comunista de [Catalonia ?] / Party Woman, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-263)
    - Harriman Trip: Rosemary / Farewell Dinner (VETS), 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-264)
    - Harriman Trip: Ross, Adolph (20-50) & [Conorson?] Store (70-90) / Sid Harris Story, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-265)
    - Harriman Trip: Spain - Grand, Rolph, [Trostel?] Concert Sphedardic Music Electronic / Janron Quanton in forthcoming towns & Jose Tarres, Oct 15, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-266)
    - Harriman Trip: Taras - Besalu & Taras - Gerona - Isaac Nahman / Rosemary (Alfred Todd), 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-267)
    - Harriman Trip: Taras - Rosemary & Sam - Lunch, Antonio de la Wenta, Tour of Barrio of the Jews, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-268)
    - Harriman Trip: Vets (Alfred Todd, Grands) / Manny with Grand in Girona, Spain, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-269)
    - Harriman Trip: Vets (VALB trip) / Vets pt. II, Oct 26, 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-270)
    - Harriman Trip: Vets (Spain), 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-271)
    - Harriman Trip: Vets (Spain), 1983 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-272)
    - [LB Speech ?], Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-273)
    - Lefkowitz, Louis: interviewed by Mary Hedge, May 21, 1981 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-274)
    - Remembering the Spanish Civil War done in England - Broadcast of Manchester Radio (50th anniversary) of Battle of Jarama, Feb 1986 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-275)
    - Schuchett, Bertha, Jan 1977 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-276)
    - Spain: a trip around Sena with (blank) telling me about [Gerona?] history of various places that go back to 900 A.D., May 5 (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-277)
    - Weisburg, Tim, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-278)
    - Unidentified Tape: 50% Speech, 50% Q&A, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-279)
    - Unidentified Tape, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-280)
    - Unidentified Tape, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-281)
    - Unidentified Tape, Undated (Box 22, Cassette ALBA V 48-282)